飙风雷哥
Rango
* 雷哥! 雷哥! *
* Rango! Rango! *
* 雷哥 *
* Rango *
今天我们齐聚一堂 用歌声纪念
We are gathered here today to immortalise in song
一位伟大传奇 短暂而不朽的一生
the life and untimely death of a great legend.
- 雷哥 - 那么 请舒服坐好 放轻松
- Rango. - So sit back, relax,
慢慢享受怀里的 低卡爆米花和各色点心
and enjoy your low-calorie popcorn and assorted confections
让我们为你讲述 这位英雄奇异 缤纷的故事
while we tell you the strange and bewildering tale of a hero
而他还不知道 自己的故事即将展开
who has yet to enter his own story.
妞妞赶牛牛佞妞妞拧牛
Crunchy, creamy, cookie, candy, cupcake.
好了 各就各位! 咱们从头开始
Okay, everybody, let's take it from the top.
舞台场景就绪 夜色因忧虑而湿润
The stage is set, the night moist with apprehension.
独处深宫 公主准备了却余生
Alone in her chamber, the princess prepares to take her own life.
"去喂蚯蚓也好过没有爱情!"
"It is far better to nourish worms than to live without love."
她端起了盛满毒酒的金杯
She reaches for the poisoned chalice.
与此同时 邪恶的马伏里奥 正密谋篡夺王位
Meanwhile, the wicked Malvolio plots his ascension to the throne
而年迈的国王陛下病入膏肓
while her ageing father lies gravely ill.
"对 我病入膏肓了..."
"Yes, I am gravely ill."
"听 什么人?"
"Hark, who goes there?"
是我! 万众期待的英雄
'Tis I, the much-anticipated hero,
回来拯救他心绪不稳的少女!
returning to rescue his emotionally unstable maiden!
把她的手放开 你这监禁美德的狱卒
Unhand her, you jailers of virtue,
不然就来尝尝我复仇之剑的滋味!
or taste the bitter sting of my vengeance!
尝尝我复... 我....
The sting of my...
马克斯博士?
Dr Marx?
马克斯博士 你怎么没反应!
Dr Marx, I'm not getting anything from you.
同志们 这点咱们已经说过了! 表演 关键就在互动
People, we've talked about this. Acting is reacting.
维克多 你刚才就像根木头! 看 我说过了
Victor, you were wooden! There, I said it.
蒂姆斯先生? 你很不错
Mr Timms? You were good.
也许有点太好了
Perhaps a little too good.
什么 维克多? 我的角色不够明确? 这太荒唐了!
What's that, Victor? My character's undefined? That's absurd.
我清楚我是谁 我是... 我就是那个人! 主角 英雄!
I know who I am. I'm the guy, the protagonist, the hero.
所有故事都需要英雄! 我是说 还有谁能有资格接受
Every story needs a hero. I mean, who else is better qualified
众多追随者的奉承?
to bask in the adulation of his numerous companions?
大幕等待拉开
The stage is waiting.
观众渴望冒险
The audience thirsts for adventure.
我是谁?
Who am I?
我可以是任何人!
I could be anyone.
我...我可以是远航归来的船长
I could be the sea cap'n returning from a mighty voyage
正要收回自己的机械臂!
to reclaim his mechanical arm!
或者是孤身探险的人类学家 在刚果丛林中与巨蟒搏斗!
Or I could be the rogue anthropologist, battling pythons down in the Congo!
啊!
Down, Chongo, down!
要是你渴望浪漫
And if you desire romance,
我就是世上最好的情人!
I will become the greatest lover the world has ever known!
我忍不住注意到 你在注意我注意你
I couldn't help but notice you noticing me noticing you.
你也应该清楚 女士们都觉得我帅到惊心
You know, the womens find me uncomfortably good looking.
不过你似乎相当自在
But you seem remarkably at ease.
哦 别这样! 别 真的...
Stop it. No, really.
好吧 如果你坚持的话! 哈 哈! 你做什么啊?
Well, if you must. What are you doing?
哦! 痒死我了! 是真的么?
That tickles. Are those real?
就是这个! 冲突!
That's it! Conflict.
维克多 你说的没错! 我确实不够明确!
Victor, you were right. I have been undefined.
同志们 我顿悟了! 虚空里不存在英雄!
People, I've had an epiphany. The hero cannot exist in a vacuum!
我们故事需要的 是一次出乎意料的突发性事件
What our story needs is an ironic, unexpected event
它将推动英雄进入冲突当中!
that will propel the hero into conflict!
蒂姆斯先生?
Mr Timms?
没错! 就是你!
That's right! You!
别害羞 过来
Don't be shy. Come on.
没事的
It's okay.
对 再过来一点
That's it, a little closer.
很好
Good.
我不会咬你的
I won't bite you.
我需要你帮点小忙
I need a little help here.
你还好吧?
Are you okay?
我必须到另一边去
I must get to the other side.
另一边? 你是说 刚才... 是你在过马路?
The other side? You mean, just now, that was you crossing the road?
所以才会...
That's why the...
你干嘛非得这么干啊?
Why'd you do that?
是我的探求 他在等我
This is my quest. He waits for me.
什么? 谁啊?
What? Who?
西部之魂 朋友 唯一之神
The Spirit of the West, amigo. The one.
听说他驾着大理石铸就的马车 有金色的守卫保护
They say he rides an alabaster carriage with golden guardians to protect him.
你说什么呢啊?
What are you talking about?
文明 没有它我们什么也不是
Enlightenment. We are nothing without it.
什么也不是? 你幻想出来的探求 刚刚毁了我的生活!
Nothing? Your delusional quest just ruined my life!
我有着极为复杂的社会关系网!
I had an incredibly complex social network going!
极为高端的朋友圈! 我非常受欢迎!
Highly sophisticated friends! I was very popular!
朋友? 我没看见什么朋友
Friends? I don't see no friends.
你是只非常寂寞的蜥蜴
You are a very lonely lizard.
听着 我需要水 水合物 我牙齿都晒裂了
Look, I need water, hydration. My teeth are chapped.
我需要护肤液 我只剩下这一层皮了
I need lotion. I'm down to one layer of skin already.
要不了多久 我就能看见自己的内部构造了
Pretty soon, I'm going to start seeing my insides.
当然 还不像你这么严重
Not unlike what you've got going there.
听着 我无法在沙漠生存 好么?
Listen, I can't survive in the desert, okay?
我... 我不属于这里
I... I don't belong here.
这倒可能是真话 不过你已经来了
That may be true, but here you are.
好了 先帮我起来 我会帮你找到你所找寻的
Now help me up and I will help you find what you seek.
- 真的? - 也许还有更多呢
- You will? - And perhaps more.
快点 我必须继续我的探求
Quickly. I must get back to my quest.
- 你是说以前你也这么干过? - 对 好多次了
- You mean you've done this before? - Yes. Many times.
快 过来 就这样 拉我的手指
Come, come. That's it, pull my finger.
西部之魂在等我
The Spirit is waiting for me.
好吧 好吧
Okay, okay.
好吧 这样根本行不通
Okay. That's not going to work.
我必须到另一边去
I must get to the other side.
那你干嘛不等 没车了再过去?
Why don't you just wait until there are no cars coming?
可没看起来那么简单
It's not so easy as it looks.
怎么?
What?
这是句隐喻
Is a metaphor.
哦 又来了一个!
There's another one!
我就知道
I knew it.
你需要帮忙么 我的朋友?
You need a little help, amigo?
我想这隐喻让我没脾气了
I think the metaphor broke my spleen.
通往真知的道路 充满了荆棘坎坷
The path to knowledge is fraught with consequence.
啊 我只是要寻找 通往水源之路
I'm just looking for the path to water.
你想找水 必须先找到"沙尘"
If you want to find water, you must first find Dirt.
沙尘?
Dirt.
命运女神对你很仁慈
Destiny, she is kind to you.
明天就是周三 水会降临
Tomorrow is Wednesday. The water comes.
正午 镇民会聚集 进行某种神秘仪式
At noon, the townspeople gather for a mysterious ritual.
喔 小镇? 你是说 有真人的地方? 在哪儿?
A town? You mean, with real people and everything? Where?
一天的脚程 沿着影子的方向走
A day's journey. Follow your shadow.
你让我往沙漠里走?
You want me to just walk out into the desert?
没错
That's the way.
好吧 那你是说
Okay. So you're saying
那里有个城镇 真正的城镇 不是什么隐喻的城镇
there's a town, a real town, not a metaphor town.
出发吧 没事的
Go on. It's okay.
好吧
Okay.
那我走了
Well, then, I'm going.
我要离开大路了!
I am leaving the road now!
我要进入沙漠了!
I'm walking into the desert!
只身一人!
Alone!
每个人都有自己的旅程
We all have our journeys to make!
我们另一边见
I will see you on the other side.
* 欢迎啊 朋友 来到 *
Welcome, amigo
* 一望无垠的土地 *
To the land without end
* 沙漠与死亡 *
The desert and death
* 是最亲密的朋友 *
Are the closest of friends
* 我们吟唱恢宏的歌曲 *
We sing of his courage
* 歌颂他的勇气 *
In magnificent song
* 但请密切注意 *
But pay close attention
* 他不会在此久活 *
He won't be here long
* 鸟儿啄食他的眼珠 烈日晒干他的血肉 *
As the birds pluck his eyes The sun bleaches his bones
* 五脏六腑遍地流 蛋蛋无影无踪 *
See his entrails get scattered Watch him lose his cojones
在莫哈韦沙漠 (位于加州西南)
Here in the Mojave Desert,
动物经过千百万年的进化 才逐渐适应了恶劣的环境
animals have had millions of years to adapt to the harsh environment.
但是这蜥蜴? 他死定了
But the lizard? He is going to die.
"87年前 我们的先辈..."
"Four score and seven years ago, our fathers..."
- 别动 - 啥?
- Don't move. - What?
- 别动! - 没动
- Don't move! - Not moving.
没动
Not moving.
伪装起来
Try to blend in.
伪装? 什么意思?
Blend in? What do you mean?
伪装
Blend in.
你说什么呐?
What are you saying?
- 太晚了 - 不不 不晚
- Too late. - No, no. It's not too late!
我在伪装 我是伪装者
I'm blending! I'm a blender!
冷静 你在干什么
Hey, calm down! What are you doing?
别动!
Stop moving!
不要看起来那么显眼
Try not to look conspicuous.
- 你干什么啊? - 伪装啊
- What are you doing? - I'm blending.
- 找其他地方躲 - 别让我分心
- Go blend somewhere else. - Don't distract me.
- 此地客满了 - 这是艺术 不是科学
- No room at the inn. - It's an art, not a science.
- 自己找地方躲去 - 不用了 这里很好
- Find your own hiding place. - No, this is good.
她来了! 赶紧跑吧 小子!
Here she comes! You better run, Mojito!
- 什么 你刚不是说"别动"吗? - 那是刚才 现在 赶快跑吧
- What? I thought you said, "Don't move." - That was before. Now, you run.
瞧你的啦 朋友
哦 嗨 鹰钩鼻
Oh, hey. Proboscis.
很暴躁啊
Testy.
不要 求你了 我有恐高症! 我要尿了!
Please, no, please. I have vertigo! My glands are swelling!
不要啊
Please, no.
嘿! 我的老妈啊!
搞什么 你 我要杀了你 臭蜥蜴!
You! I'll kill you! You stupid lizard!
滚出来 我要捏碎你的蛋蛋!
Get out of there. I'm going to strangle your huevos!
大鸟! 大鸟来了!
Big bird! Big bird!
等等我 回来! 我刚才开玩笑的!
No, wait! Come back! I was just kidding!
- 别这样 我们是朋友 - 我不认识你!
- Come on, we're friends, right? - I don't know you!
- 蜥蜴 青蛙... - 找其他地方躲!
- Lizards, frogs... - Find your own hiding place!
- 本来就是一家嘛! - 此地客满了!
- We're practically related! - No room at the inn!
- 别小气嘛 挪过去点! - 你不是我朋友!
- Come on, move over! - You're not my friend!
大不了我让你吻我妹妹!
I'll let you kiss my sister!
你这个混...
You son of a...
伙计 你的朋友呢 ?
Where are your friends now, amigo?
把你长蹼的泥手 从我靴子上拿开!
Get your slimy-webbed phalanges off my boots!
抱歉
Sorry.
我瞄准你了 陌生人 现在慢慢站起来
I got a bead on you, stranger. So you get up real slow
除非你想花整个下午
lessen you want to spend the better part
把爆了的脸重新拼起来
of the afternoon putting your face back together!
- 不不 女侠 我不想 - 你是谁?
- No, ma'am, I don't. - Who are you?
- 我是谁? - 这里只有我能问问题!
- Who am I? - I'm asking the questions here!
我们的镇子遇到干旱 水都没了
Our town is drying up. We're in the middle of a drought.
现在却有人在沙漠里倒水
Now someone's dumping water in the desert!
这是个深不可测的谜团
It's a puzzle of undeterminable size and dimension,
不过我想知道你在其中 扮演的是什么角色
but I intend to find out what role you playing in all this.
- 角色? - 你都做过些什么?
- Role? - What are you involved in?
哦哦 问得好
Well, I'm glad you asked.
我有两出独幕剧 一出悬疑剧 还有一出音乐剧在创意中
I've got two one-acts, a mystery and a musical I've been gestating.
歌词已经写好了 正在创作旋律 风格是...
I got the words, I'm just working on the melody right now. It's like a...
应该是西部风格的
I think it's gonna be a western.
* 一只猴找了个妞 他母亲是个荡妇 *
A monkey got a cracker His mother was a slapper
* 她会冒着大雨进山来 *
She'll be coming 'round the mountain in the rain
你不是本地人 是吧
You ain't from around here, are you?
呃 还在努力中
I'm still working on it.
对了 你叫什么名字
So, what's your name?
- 豆豆 - 这名字挺逗的
- Beans. - That's a funny kind of name.
我有什么办法 谁让我爸超级喜欢烘豆子
What can I say? My daddy plumb loved baked beans.
幸好你爸不是喜欢芦笋
Well, you're lucky he didn't plumb love asparagus.
你说什么
What are you saying?
我是说 我个人很喜欢丰盛的娼妇酱 (某种意大利酱料)
I mean, I enjoy a hearty puttanesca myself,
但我不确定 孩子会喜欢这种花名
but I'm not sure that a child would appreciate the moniker.
我爸爸是个好人 虽然他对豆类有特殊癖好
My daddy was a great man, even if he did exhibit a proclivity for legumes.
- 美味 - 你在吃他的灰
- Spicy. - You're eating his ashes!
你带着他的骨灰?
You carry his remains?
不 是他的烟灰 他喜欢抽烟 他们没有找到尸体
No, his ashes. He loved to smoke. They never found the body.
肯定有他的理由
Well, I'm sure he had his reasons.
- 你什么意思 - 没什么
- What are you implying? - Nothing.
我爸从未靠近过矿井
My daddy was never near that mine shaft.
他已经一个月没喝酒了!
He'd been sober for over a month!
如果你暗示他会在 我人格发展的敏感阶段
And for you to insinuate that he would abandon his parental responsibilities
不履行父母责任 就是对我的侮...
at a delicate time in my personal development is an affront to my sense...
豆豆小姐?
Miss Beans?
豆豆小姐? 嗨?
Miss Beans? Hello?
嗨
Hello?
除非仙女座五号的人
And until the people of Andromeda Five
放他平安无事的回来 我就不会卖了我的农场!
return him safe and sound, I will not sell my ranch!
- 什...你在干什么? - 你在干什么?
- What... What are you doing? - What are you doing?
- 我在干什么? - 你搂着我呢
- What am I doing? - You're cuddling me.
- 你刚才定住了 - 我没有
- You were frozen. - I was not.
你有 你突然不说话了
Yes, you were. You stopped talking.
这是种防御机制 很多蜥蜴都会
It's a defence mechanism. Actually, lots of lizards have it.
你编的吧
You're making that up.
那么 你是想死在这里  还是搭顺风车去镇里?
So, you gonna die out here, or you want a ride into town?
不不不 好的 不 好的 谢谢 抱歉
No, no, no. Yeah. No. Yes, please. Thank you. Sorry.
今天是周三 周三大家都会进镇
Today's Wednesday. Wednesday's when we all get to it.
那你到底是谁啊
So who are you, really?
哦 我有很多绰号
Well, I'm a man of many epithets.
艺名 笔名 代号
There's my stage name, my pen name, my avatar.
我以前还有个假名 后来合法变更了
I had a pseudonym once, but I had it legally changed.
于是寻找伴侣的陌生人
And so the stranger, seeking companionship,
遇到了一个女子 像极了古时的女妖
finds the woman, much like the sirens of ancient times
诱惑他前往未知的死亡
luring him to his certain demise.
...不是说这个我很自豪 不过
...nom de plume, I have a CB handle.
我还是少数几个 有娘家名的男人
I'm actually one of the few men with a maiden name.
喔! 我们到了
Whoa! Well, here we are.
对对
Right.
非常感谢 豆豆小姐
Well, I sure do appreciate this, Miss Beans,
- 如果有什么我能... - 驾
- and if there's ever anything that I... - Get on up!
好吧
Okay, then!
再见 豆豆
See you, Beans.
欢迎来到 沙尘镇
你也要走了 Jim?
You heading out, Jim?
我们尽了最大努力了  不得不倾家荡产离开
Well, we gave it our best shot. We had to sell out.
没有水就种不出庄稼
Can't grow no crops without no water.
再见了
Bye, now!
怪家伙
What is it?
这是干什么
What was that for?
你长得好滑稽
You're funny looking.
是吗 你也长得很滑稽
Oh, yeah? Well, you're funny looking, too.
- 你的衬衫好滑稽 - 你的裙子好滑稽
- That's a funny-looking shirt. - That's a funny-looking dress.
- 你的眼睛好滑稽 - 你的脸好滑稽
- You got funny-looking eyes! - You got a funny-looking face!
你是陌生人 陌生人在这里活不久的
You're a stranger. Strangers don't last long here.
你的豆子 豆豆
Here's your beans, Beans.
这次我还想 多要一些饲料 威利
I'm gonna need some more feed, too, Willie.
豆豆 你已经欠我三夸脱了 不能再给你赊账了
Now, Beans, you owe me three quarts already. I can't give you more credit.
但我中午就能还清了
But I'll have what I owe you at noon.
你不明白 是银行的梅里马克先生 他断了所有赊账
You don't understand. It's Mr Merrimack down at the bank. He cut off all credit.
嗨 豆豆! 豆豆!
Hey, Beans! Beans!
你认识那家伙?
You know that there fella?
嗨 豆豆 豆豆小姐
Hey, Beans! Miss Beans!
不认识
Nope.
嗨 豆豆
Hey, Beans!
嗨
Hey.
对了 伪装 伪装混入人群
Right. Blend in. Yeah, blend in.
我想要杯水
I'd like a glass of water.
他想要杯水
He wants a glass of water!
来双份
Make it a double!
给他痰盂
Give him the spittoon!
仙人掌汁 只有这个
Cactus juice. That's what we got.
嗨 花衬衫
Hey, there, fruit cup.
你来自远乡吧 嗯?
You're a long ways from home, ain't ya?
你到底是谁啊?
Who exactly are you?
我是谁
Who am I?
我可以是任何人
I could be anyone.
怎么了 想念妈妈的咪咪了吗?
What's the matter? You missing your mommy's mangos?
事实上 是的
As a matter of fact, I am.
但更想你老爸做的菜!
But not as much as your daddy's cooking!
你说你是哪里人来着?
Exactly where did you say you were from?
我? 我来自西部
Me? I'm from the West.
那边 地平线的另一头 日落的尽头
Out there, beyond the horizon. Past the sunset.
远西区
The Far West.
没错 先生们
Yeah, that's right, hombres.
在我的家乡 早饭前杀人
The place I come from, we kill a man before breakfast
仅当开胃
just to work up an appetite.
然后倒上盐和胡椒
Then we salt him, and we pepper him.
用澄清黄油炖熟 然后吃掉
Then we braise him in clarified butter. And then we eat him.
- 你们吃人? - 不要重复我
- You eat him? - That's what I said!
我的所见所闻 能让成年男人丧失肾上腺功能
Hell, I seen things make a grown man lose control of his glandular functions!
在马骸骨里住上三天 靠自己的尿液生存
You spend three days in a horse carcass, living off your own juices.
这会改变一个人 是啊
It'll change a man. Oh, yeah.
好像多了几张A 我喜欢这样
Had a few extra aces in this deck, gents. Just the way I like it.
所以 没错 毛绒鼠朋友 我的确不是本地人
So, no, my hirsute little rodent friend, I am not from around these parts.
我来自一个充满危险
You might say I'm from everywhere there's trouble brewing
地狱般的国度
and hell waiting to be raised.
也许就是地狱
You might say I'm what hell's already raised up.
我的名字叫
Name's
雷哥
Rango.
就是你杀了詹金斯兄弟?
Are you the fella that killed them Jenkins brothers?
一枪毙命
Killed them with one bullet.
死的透透的
Don't get no deader.
所有七个?
All seven of them?
没错
That's right.
所有七个
All seven of them.
您到底是怎么办到的 雷哥先生?
Exactly how you do that, Mr Rango?
问得好
You know, I'm glad you asked me that.
我很乐意告诉大家 不过听好了
And I will be happy to tell you how. But you're all gonna have to listen up!
因为这会变得很...
Because this is where it gets
复杂
complicated.
这是您账户上所有的了 奥茨太太 两小口加一大口
That'll close out your account, Mrs Oats, two gulps and a swig.
别碰 末底改 这是你剩余的教育基金
Hands off, Mordecai! That's what's left of your college education!
我别无选择 豆豆
I don't rightly have no other choice, Beans.
如今世道艰难 不能再赊账了
Times being so hard, we just can't give no more credit.
但这里是银行 水都存在这儿
But this here is a bank. This is where you keep the water.
豆豆 我待你一直像亲侄女一样 自从你爹...
Beans, you've been like a niece to me ever since your daddy
没有喝醉失足掉进矿井
did not fall drunk down a mine shaft.
我一直试图保护你和大家 瞒着某些残酷的现实
I've tried to protect you and others from certain realities.
但是...
But that... Well...
- 梅里马克先生? - 现实要崩溃了
- Mr Merrimack? - Realities are bearing down.
梅里马克先生
Mr Merrimack!
你还好吧
Are you all right?
豆豆 我要给你看些东西
Beans, I need to show you something.
- 只剩这些了? - 这已经是储备水了
- That's all that's left? - And this here is the reserve!
不知道你有没有注意
I don't know if you've noticed,
人们已经不再在周三存水了
but folks just ain't making deposits on a Wednesday no more!
梅里马克先生 如果弄不到水 我就会失去农场
Mr Merrimack, if I don't get some water, I'm gonna lose my ranch
而你现在告诉我 整个镇子只有这些水了?
and you're telling me that's all that's left in the whole town?
这根本说不通 好了 听着
Now that just don't make no sense. Now, listen.
有人在沙漠里倒水
Someone is dumping water in the desert.
我亲眼看见的
I seen it with my own eyes.
沙漠里有水?
Water in the desert?
是你在特殊状态下看到的吗
Was this during one of your special times?
不是
No.
人人都可以做梦 但这就是现实
Well, we can all dream, but this is the reality.
你以为怎么有这么多人离开? 因为他们生活不下去了
Why do you think so many people are selling out? They just can't make it.
那我该怎么办
Well, what am I supposed to do?
我觉得可以跟镇长谈谈
Well, I suppose we could talk to the Mayor.
听说他一直在帮助大家度过危机
I hear he's been helping people out in this time of crisis.
镇长?
The Mayor?
他可能是我们唯一的希望
He may be our only hope.
子弹击中的铁锹 反弹到了第三个
Bullet hits a shovel, ricochets back towards number three,
这时屋顶坍塌了
and that's when the roof caved in,
点燃了装满酒精的瓶子
igniting the thermos of pure grain alcohol
瞬间蒸发了他的肉体 只剩一堆黑炭
instantly vapourising his bodily form, leaving nothing but a charcoal statue
和高亢的尖叫
and a high-pitched squeal.
等一下 这只是六个 第七个怎么样了
Hold on, there. That's only six. What happened to number seven?
第七个?
Number seven?
他死于感染
Hell, he died of infection.
- 七个人 - 一枪毙命
- Seven men! - One bullet!
随便喝
Drinks all around!
跳啊 乡巴佬
Dance for me, Sod Buster!
- 跳得跟小鸡似的 - 没错 跳啊
- Yes, dance like a chicken! - That's right! Dance!
你听不懂吗 朋友
You got corn in your ears, mate?
不付抵押 就有没有土地
You don't pay the mortgage, you don't own the land!
- 这是基本房地产法 - 等价交换
- That's basic real estate law, my friend. - Quid pro quo!
再让我在镇上看到你的脸
If I see your face in this town again,
我就把它切开 用来擦我那不可告人之处
I'm gonna slice it off and use it to wipe my unmentionables.
小心鸟嘴
Mind the beak.
不许再回来
And don't come back!
看什么看
What are you all gawping at?
嘿 坏比尔 我有事要告诉你
Hey, Bad Bill, there's something I got to tell you!
这是谁啊
What is this?
知道这是谁吗 比尔 他是雷哥
You know who that is, Bill? That there's Rango!
他不怕你 不怕你们任何人
Yeah, he ain't afraid of you! He ain't afraid of none of you.
他杀了詹金斯兄弟
Killed them Jenkins brothers.
- 一枪毙命 比尔 - 所有七个
- Done it with one bullet, Bill. - All seven of them!
是吗
Is that right?
让我来...
Let me get that before you...
我知道了 来
No. Oh, I know. Here.
我来帮你
Just take care of that for you.
好多了
There. All better.
暂停 暂停 等一下
T.O. T.O. Just a second.
好了 听着
All right, now listen!
我给你最后一次机会 重新考虑
I'm going to give you fellas one last chance to reconsider!
如果你们不用重新考虑
And if you don't want to reconsider
那我可能自己要重新考虑下
I might consider reconsidering myself.
我说的就是这意思 啊
Now that's what I'm talking about. Yeah.
好了 听着
All right, now listen up!
现在雷哥我来了 规矩就得改改
Things are going to be different around here now that Rango's in town.
有新规定 每天早上 我的鞋要干干净净的
Got some new rules! I want my shoes shined every morning,
要有热咖啡 配丹麦面包
my coffee hot, Danish on the side.
不管做什么 都不许直视我的眼睛
Whatever you do, don't look me in the eye.
离开我的周围视野
Stay out of my peripheral vision!
- 是雷哥 - 他要干什么啊?
- It's Rango. - What's he up to?
他天不怕地不怕 正跟那鸟讲规矩
He ain't afraid of nobody. He's telling that bird what's for!
看到我来 就要让开
And when you see me coming, stand aside.
我步子很大 我可不想靴子上
I take large steps and I don't want none of you hayseeds
沾到你们乡巴佬的体液
getting your bodily fluids on my boots!
当然 不要诉诸暴力
Of course, there is no need for violence,
只要我们团结在一起 团队作战
as long as we stick together, work as a team.
大家都出来 站成一列
So I want you all to come outside now and line up single file
我稍事休息
while I take a brief intermission!
他现在在干吗
What's he doing now?
可能是B计划
I think it's a number two.
没事
Never mind.
看这边
Take a look-see over here!
快看他
Well, look at him now!
他在追大鹰
He's chasing after that hawk!
让他好看 雷哥
Give him hell, Rango!
- 你们看到了吗 - 他杀了那家伙
- Did you see that? - He killed that thing!
你怎么看 医生
What do you think, Doc?
这鹰死了
This hawk is dead!
哇 不如烧了吃吧
Shoot, I say we cook that right up.
只用了一粒子弹
He did it with one bullet!
就跟他说的一样
Just like he said!
我们终于有英雄了
It's about time we had a hero around here.
没躲在木头箱子里
One who ain't in a pine box.
该让他见见镇长了
I think it's time he met the Mayor.
你听到了吗 雷哥?  你要去见镇长了!
You hear that, Rango? You're going to meet the Mayor!
为雷哥欢呼吧!
Let's hear it for Rango!
于是陌生人沉浸在
And so the stranger basks
新朋友的赞美之词中
in the adulation of his new friends,
在自己编造的甜蜜骗局里越陷越深
sinking deeper into the guacamole of his own deception.
他什么时候死啊?
When is he going to die?
快了 伙计 快了
Soon, compadre. Soon.
我的地不卖!
My land is not for sale!
我是来争取它 不是来卖的!
I came here to save my land, not sell it!
如果你跟他谈谈 肯定能想出合理的办法!
I'm sure there's something reasonable we can work out if you just talk to him!
豆豆! 你上哪儿去? 豆豆?
Beans! Where are you going? Beans?
你现在可以进去见镇长了
The Mayor will see you now.
水啊 雷哥先生 万能的水
Water, Mr Rango, water.
缺了水就只剩尘土与腐尸
Without it, there's nothing but dust and decay.
但有水 就有生命
But with water there's life.
瞧它们 极力求生 哪里有水就去哪里
Look at them, so desperate to live, they'll follow it anywhere.
这是沙漠中亘古不变的定理
That's the immutable law of the desert.
有水在手 万事不愁
Control the water and you control everything.
不过既然你是真正的西部人 我就不必多说了
But I don't have to tell you that being a true man of the West, as you are.
当然了 西部...无限好 (大门乐队的歌)
Oh, yeah. The West is the best.
这是从我小金库里拿的
This is from my private stock.
来自大洪水时期的上等雨水
Vintage rainwater from the Great Deluge.
不是诺亚洪水  老天 我还没那么老
Not Noah's deluge. Good heavens, I'm not that old.
我想权力能带来特惠
I guess power has its privileges.
说得有道理 孩子
You make a good point, son.
但特惠意味着责任
But with privilege comes responsibility.
我当镇长的日子比这镇子还久!
Hell, I was mayor here before there was a Dirt!
也许只是我这老海龟瞎感慨
And I may be just a sentimental old turtle
但我认为这镇子还有救 我希望你加入我们
but I think there's a future for this town. And I hope you'll be part of it.
- 敬沙尘镇! - 敬沙尘镇!
- To Dirt! - To Dirt.
雷哥先生 你看见了吗? 我所有的朋友和邻居
You see them, Mr Rango? All my friends and neighbours?
这里的生活很难 非常艰辛
It's a hard life here. Very hard.
你知道他们是靠什么过来的?
Do you know how they make it through each and every day?
靠信仰
They believe.
他们相信日子会好起来
They believe it's going to be better.
相信天终究会下雨
They believe that the water will come.
在明摆着的事实 和渺茫的希望面前仍相信
They believe against all odds and all evidence
明天会更好
that tomorrow will be better than today.
人们必须有信仰
People have to believe in something.
现在 他们相信你
Right now, they believe in you.
拿起它 雷哥先生  命运在召唤你
Pick it up, Mr Rango. Your destiny awaits.
人们必须有信仰
People have to believe in something.
快要正午了 都准备好了?
It's almost noon. Is everything ready?
是 但他可能是个问题
Yeah. But he might be a problem.
他不是问题 威廉 而是答案
He's not a problem, William. He's a solution.
这没道理啊
It just don't make no sense.
整个镇子都在枯竭
This whole town is drying up,
镇长好像是唯一不着急的人
and the Mayor is the only one who don't seem to be affected.
你难道没有一丁点儿怀疑?
Doesn't that make you just a wee bit suspicious?
还有我在沙漠里看到的水呢?
And what about that water I saw out in the desert?
好了好了!  不必太焦虑 我去问问镇长
All right! No need to incite anxiety. I'll inquire about the Mayor.
但如果你真感觉里面有鬼
But if you really feel there's some conspiracy occurring,
我建议你还是去找新治安官
I suggest you take it up with the new sheriff.
挺合身的 喂! 小心针
This is going to be good. Hey! Watch that needle there.
别太紧 我要留点皱褶!
Not too tight. I want to leave room for some pucker!
这样很好
That's good.
放轻松 大小姐
Oh, easy there, tiger.
- 往后上方改改? - 我觉得不要
- A little up and back? - I don't think so.
能做个双层袖口吗?
Have you got French cuffs with that?
打扰了 雷哥治安官 我要和你谈谈
Excuse me, Sheriff Rango. I want to talk to you.
嘿 豆豆 你觉得新制服如何?
Hey, Beans, what do you think of the new duds?
我把15加仑的帽子 还成10加仑了
I got a 10-gallon hat marked down from 15.
- 很漂亮 - 你见过安杰莉克了吗?
- That's nice. - Have you met Angelique?
- 你好 豆豆 - 你好 安杰莉克
- Hello, Beans. - Hello, Angelique.
- 骚货 - 荡妇
- Tart. - Floozy.
- 妓女 - 请问雷哥先生
- Trollop. - Excuse me, Mr Rango.
信不信我用这把枪 打爆你的脸!
I will blow that ugly right off your face!
我只不过是想...
I was just thinking that...
你是想要亲笔签名吧?
You want the old John Hancock, do you?
- 来 帮我拿着 - 雷哥治安官 我不是来跟你拉家常的
- Well, here. Hold this. - Sheriff Rango, this isn't a social call.
里面有颗子弹
There's a bullet in there.
知道知道 今天下午的舞会嘛
I know about the shindig this afternoon.
- 我给自己做了一套正式的礼服 - 治安官 我想报案...
- I ordered myself some right fancy duds. - Sheriff, I'd like to file a...
- 雷哥先生! - 你也要? 没问题
- Mr Rango! - Oh, you, too? No problem.
- 来 让我... - 我想请你调查...
- Here, let me just... - I need you to investigate...
豆豆 我想你也打扮打扮 可得花点心思
You know, Beans, I bet you clean up real nice, you put a little effort into it.
- 什么? - 记住咯 孩子
- What? - Now, remember, son,
不要逃课 多吃蔬菜  除了莎士比亚其他都烧掉
stay in school, eat your veggies, burn everything but Shakespeare.
- 谁是莎士比亚? - 雷哥治安官
- Who's Shakespeare? - Sheriff Rango,
如果这是你真名的话
if that is your real name.
我正在努力拯救我父亲的农场
I am trying to save my daddy's ranch,
那里快要沦为荒地了
which is on the verge of an agricultural meltdown
你却在这里和妓女玩过家家!
while you're playing patty-cake with this here trollop!
真可悲 多乏味的小东西啊
Sad, really. Such a drab little thing.
她为什么会这样?
Why does she do that?
- 这是生存反射 - 就是开关坏了
- It's a survival reflex. - Her switch is just broken.
这可真不方便
Well, that's an inconvenience.
这不是疹子! 是胎记!
It is not a rash! It is a birthmark!
我又那样了 对吗?
I did it again, didn't I?
哪样?
Did what?
我来问你
Let me ask you something.
有人提到过 上一任治安官的下场吗?
Did anybody here mention what happened to our last sheriff?
对不起 我想请问... 打扰了 请问一下...
Pardon, but may I ask you... Excuse me, may I ask you...
上任治安官...对不起 大家这是要去哪儿?
The last sheriff... Pardon me. Where is everybody going?
到底出什么事了...
What exactly happened to the...
* 一整天 *
All day
* 我干瞪着贫瘠的土壤 *
I've faced the barren waste
* 却尝不到水的滋味 *
Without the taste of water
* 清凉的水啊 *
Cool water
* 老丹尼和我 *
Old Dan and I
* 嗓子干得冒了烟儿 *
With throats burned dry
* 灵魂渴求着 *
And souls that cry
* 甘甜的水 *
For water
* 清清... *
Cool
真抱歉 真抱歉
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
* 凉凉的水啊 *
Clear water
你们这乡村舞可真够特别的
This is a heck of a hoedown you got going.
舞步我还要练练
Still working out those steps.
这属于正常的市民行为吗?
So, is this considered normal civic behaviour?
对啊 每周三  和钟点一样准时
Every Wednesday, just like clockwork.
你杀了大鸟
You kill bird.
没错 千真万确
Yeah. Matter of fact, I did.
鸟死 蛇就来
Bird dead. Snake come.
蛇?
Snake?
他说的是响尾蛇詹克 雷哥先生
He means Rattlesnake Jake, Mr Rango.
他从不来镇上 因为他怕老鹰
He never comes to town 'cause he's scared of that hawk.
不过现在可能会来了
But he might come now.
你死后我能穿你的靴子吗?
Can I have your boots when you're dead?
不行!
No!
我可不怕什么响尾蛇詹克
And I ain't got no problem with this Rattlesnake Jake.
阿莫也是这样说的
That's just what Amos said.
阿莫?
Amos?
治安官阿莫之墓 在任时间 周四-周六
你有金牙吗?
You got any gold fillings?
我亲爱的沙尘镇镇民们
My fellow Dirtonians.
欢迎各位参加解渴大节 哈利路亚
I welcome you to our great day of deliverance. Hallelujah.
- 哈利路亚! - 哈利路亚!
- Hallelujah! - Hallelujah!
侍僧 呈上圣栓!
Acolytes, prepare the holy spigot!
今天我们有一位新成员 朋友们
We have a newcomer amongst us today, my friends.
我想需要为你们介绍一下
A man I think needs little introduction to you
他一来这个平等社区 就表现出了非凡的勇气
so bold has been his entry into our fair society.
雷哥先生 请你上前来
Mr Rango, would you step forward?
时机已到 朋友们  预言中的时刻!
The time has come, my friends. The time that was foretold!
- 哈利路亚! - 哈利路亚!
- Hallelujah! - Hallelujah!
神圣的时刻!
The sacred time!
- 哈利路亚! - 哈利路亚!
- Hallelujah! - Hallelujah!
命运注定的时刻!
The time of destiny!
- 哈利路亚! - 哈利路亚!
- Hallelujah! - Hallelujah!
获得解脱的时刻!
The time of deliverance!
- 哈利路亚! - 哈利路亚!
- Hallelujah! - Hallelujah!
沐浴清泉的时刻到了!
It is the time of hydration!
- 都怪他! - 都是因为新人!
- It's his fault! - It's the newcomer!
- 烧死他! - 他是巫师!
- Burn him! - He's a witch!
我要他的靴子!
I get his boots!
我的朋友们 我的朋友们 请冷静一点
My friends, my friends! Temper your frustrations.
现在起形势会变得严峻 必须有人做出牺牲
Times will be tough from now on. Sacrifices will have to be made.
但如果我能帮忙  请随时过来...
But if I can help in any way, please know that my door is always...
慢着 慢着!
Hold it, hold it!
整件事有很多疑点
Now, this whole thing stinks three ways to Sunday.
先是银行枯竭 现在又是这个水栓?
First the bank's run dry and now this here spigot?
银行枯竭?
The bank's run dry?
- 她说什么呢? - 她说银行没水了!
- What's she talking about? - She said there's no water in the bank!
我们只剩这些了! 不能都给你们!
This is all we have! We can't give it all out!
那可是我的补水账户!
That was my rehydration account!
我的治安范围内不得出现骚乱 非常感谢
None of that civil disobedience in my town, thank you very much.
谢天谢地您来了 治安官大人 这里有点失控
Thank goodness you're here, Sheriff. Things were getting out of hand.
快请进
Come right in.
我来瞧瞧这场社会不安的根源
Let me have a gander at the source of the societal discontentment here.
老天爷
Mercy.
好了 给我听着! 我想过了
All right, listen up! I've been thinking
而且我认为 我得出了一点结论
and I believe I've figured something out.
你们镇有水资源危机!
You folks have a water problem!
现在大家注意了  我要说的话相当重要
Now just pay attention, everybody. I'm trying to make a point here.
比方说有个家伙要喝口水
Let's say this fella here were to take a drink of water.
只要一小口 没什么大碍 对吧?
Just one little drink. No harm, no foul, right?
接着是你!
And you!
你口干舌燥  就像七月的长耳兔
You're just as dried up and parched as a jackrabbit in July.
所以你鼓起勇气尝试了第二口!
So you belly on up and take you a double shot!
挺住
Stay with me.
然后会怎么样? 如果我们都来喝!
What do you think happens then? Why we'd all be drinking!
在你们意识到之前 已经滴水不剩了
And before you know it, there wouldn't be any more water.
然后我们会怎么样?
And then where would we be?
我们就会口渴
We'd be thirsty.
非常口渴
Real thirsty.
我们会像禽兽一样对待彼此!
We'd turn on each other like a bunch of animals!
现在请看 我们有六天的水
Now look here. We have got six days of water.
我们有五天...
We have got five days...
只要还有水 我们就能保住镇子
As long as we've got water, we've got ourselves a town.
雷哥治安官说得对
Sheriff Rango is right.
只要还有水 我们就有希望
As long as we have this water, we have some hope.
我向各位承诺
And you can all take it from me.
即刻起 我工作的全部职责
My 100o/o full-time employment from this moment on
就是保护这珍贵的自然资源
will be to protect our precious natural resource.
没人能跟我雷哥作对
Ain't no one gonna tango with the Rango.
晚上好 女士们
Evening, ladies.
晚上好 治安官
Evening, Sheriff.
休想再给我进来!
And don't you come back!
坚持住 戈迪 你进去重申自己的立场
Hold on there, Gordy. You get back in there and you assert yourself,
你会发现镇上的人 出奇的好客
and I think you'll find the people of this here town to be surprisingly hospitable.
谢谢你 治安官
Thank you, Sheriff.
什么? 别再来了!
What? Not you again!
我承认错误
I stand corrected.
- 这里不是银行 - 我告诉过你 杰迪代亚!
- This ain't the bank. - I told you, Jedidiah!
待着不许动!
Hold it right there!
- 那是谁? - 是治安官!
- Who's that? - It's the Sheriff!
把手举到我能看见的地方!
Get them hands up where I can see them!
我果然没猜错
Just as I suspected.
勘察时没有使用官方设备 一根手指也别动
Prospecting without the authorised equipment. Don't move a muscle.
勘察?
Prospecting?
现在你们有铁铲 铁镐  伤风抗素剂 丝瓜球
Now, you got your shovel, pickaxe, Benadryl, loofah,
各种零食 猜谜游戏 你们还需一张许可证
assorted snacks, some puzzle books and you're gonna need a permit.
- 丝瓜球 - 伊齐基尔 杰迪代亚!
- Loofah. - Ezekiel, Jedidiah!
上面他妈怎么了?
What the Sam Hill's going on up there?
我把息肉割了 都比你们两个聪明
I've had polyps removed smarter than the two of you!
真是倒霉 这又不是银行
Hell's fire, this ain't the bank!
老爸 治安官就在这 他正帮我们呢
Pappy, the Sheriff is standing right here, helping us out.
他会给咱开个勘探许可证
Gonna give us a permit for prospecting.
没错 先生 这是我应该做的
That's right, sir. Just doing my duty.
一名正在巡逻的寂寞警探
The lonely constable on his rounds,
鹰一般的眼睛四处巡视 残害和不法行为
keeping an eagle eye out for mayhem and malfeasance.
他看起来像他说的那样?
Does he look like he sounds?
好吧 治安官 如果我们要找到主矿
Well, Sheriff, if we was to hit the mother lode,
成为勘探家之类的
being prospectors and such,
我们去哪存年金保险?
where would we deposit said annuity?
在沙尘镇这里就行啊 我们正好有一家
Here in the town of Dirt, we happen to have
密苏里州顶级的财政机构
the finest financial institution this side of the Missouri.
由鄙人24小时加以保护
Protected morning, noon and night by yours truly.
非常感谢
Much obliged.
银行被抢了 银行被抢了
The bank's been robbed! The bank's been robbed!
上帝啊 银行被抢了
Good Lord, the bank's been robbed!
发生什么事了
What's going on?
- 没了 水都没了 - 他说什么
- It's gone! The water's all gone! - What'd he say?
他说银行被抢了
He said the bank's been robbed!
马克斯博士 我着火了 快抱我
Dr Marx! I'm on fire! Embrace me!
* 银行被抢了 小镇干枯了 人们哭着说 "我们会渴死" *
The bank's been robbed, the town is dry "We'll die of thirst," the people cry
* 他答应要保护储藏室 水全没了 这都是他的错 *
He promised to protect the vault The water's gone, it's all his fault
好了 乡亲们 往后站 清场了
All right, folks, stand back, clear the area.
现在这里是犯罪现场
This is a crime scene now.
盯紧周边  清出脚印 检查纤维 扫描DNA
Secure the perimeter, dust for prints, check for fibres, scan for DNA.
我需要采集所有人的尿样 给我来杯拿铁
I want a urine sample from everyone. And get me a latte.
别把这两个弄混了
And don't mix up the two.
这是什么
What's this?
"勘探许可证"
"Prospecting Permit."
给我 这是物证
I'll take that. Material evidence.
我们现在怎么办 治安官?
What are we gonna do now, Sheriff?
- 我们需要水 - 我们都会死的
- We need that water. - We're all going to die!
朋友们 我们都知道现在必须做什么
My friends, we all know what we have to do now.
没错 我们都知道现在必须做什么
That's right. We all know what we have to do now.
- 做什么呢? - 成立一支武装队
- And that would be? - Form a posse.
成立一只负鼠
Form a possum!
武装队
A posse.
现在我们要积极有序的做这件事
Now, we're gonna be doing this in an orderly fashion.
首先 有人知道如何使用任何武器吗
First off, does anybody here know how to use a firearm of any kind?
那好吧
All right, then.
现在我们怎么办 治安官?
What do we do now, Sheriff?
现在 上马出发!
Now we ride!
我们要去哪
Where are we going?
什么
What?
我们要去哪
Where are we going?
好 作为我的副手 你负责跟踪及寻找坏蛋
Now, as my deputy, you'll be in charge of all tracking and finding of villains,
充分发挥你的天赋本领 别在意哈
utilising your well-developed Injun-uity, no offence taken.
你觉得他们会走哪条路?
So which way do you think they went?
你要不要嗅嗅空气 和野牛交谈之类的?
You want to sniff the air or commune with a buffalo or something?
噢 你很棒啊
Oh, you're good.
我靠你了 勺子
I'm depending on you, Spoons.
你胡子里有点烟屑
You got a little tobaccy in the beard there.
你随时在身边真好 医生
Always good to have a medical man along, Doc.
我们爬行动物要团结友爱 对吗 兄弟
Reptiles got to stick together, right, my brother?
我是两栖动物
I'm an amphibian.
不要觉得丢脸
Ain't no shame in that.
你确定你能干好这工作 大兵?
You sure you're fit for duty there, soldier?
你眼睛里有个东西
Well, you got a little something in your eye there.
噢 那个吗 我有结膜炎 长官 是遗传病
Oh, that? That there's conjunctivitis, sir. It's hereditary.
好吧 还好不是传染病
Well, I'm glad to hear it's not contagious.
等等 等一下下 武装队可不是...
Now, just wait a cotton-picking minute! A posse ain't no place for a...
算我没说
Never mind.
等等 小妹妹
Hold on there, little sister.
我走了得有人照看这镇子啊
Someone's gonna have to look after the town while I'm gone.
我能一枪打死谁吗
Can I gut-shoot someone?
咱们还是先上上保险栓哈
Let's put a pin in that.
治安官 你会把水带回来的 对吗
Sheriff, you're going to bring that water back, aren't you?
放心吧 小妹妹
Count on it, little sister.
- 我们往哪走 治安官? - 到处都是隧道
- Which way do we go, Sheriff? - There's tunnels everywhere.
整个镇千疮百孔
Whole town's perforated with them.
比油画里豪猪上的女人 身上洞还多
He got more holes in him than even a painted lady on a porcupine.
嘿 我爸带我去过她家
Hey, my daddy took me to her place.
跟我想象中不太一样
Not what I expected.
这些家伙到底怎么找到银行的
How'd them fellers find the bank, anyway?
先生们  我们能不能专注于我们的任务
Gentlemen, if we can just stay on task here.
治安官  过来这边
Sheriff! Over here!
- 瞧瞧啊 - 就像看着上帝的脸
- Would you look at that? - Like seeing the face of God.
阿门 兄弟
Amen, brother.
我还记得每周三它都会流动
I remember when it used to flow every Wednesday.
多么太平幸福的日子
Those were the halcyon days.
她放弃我们肯定是有原因的
Must be a reason she quit on us.
不管是什么原因 肯定有人在控制这的水
Whatever the reason, something is controlling this here water.
你说呢  治安官
What do you say, Sheriff?
很明显 强盗们是从这个方向来的
Clearly, the robbers came from this direction.
我建议我们沿着这管道走 找到它的水源
I say we track this pipe back to its hydraulic origin
然后活捉偷水案背后的罪魁祸首
and apprehend the culprits behind this aquatic conundrum.
- 他说什么 - 我想他说的是 沿着管道走
- What'd he say? - I think he said follow the pipe.
- 他说沿着管道走 - 他说沿着管道走
- He said follow the pipe. - He said follow the pipe.
这下面可真潮湿啊
Sure is humid down here.
是啊 就像一个大泥堆
Yeah. It's like the big mud piles.
我曾经移除过一个甲状腺肿块
I had a goitre removed once.
看起来就像托尼・班尼特刚刚出浴
Looked like Tony Bennett stepping out of the shower.
我把那个放玉米饼上了
I put that on a tortilla.
不管做什么 千万别往下看
Whatever you do, do not look down.
- 这是什么地方 - 一个地下蓄水层
- What is this place? - It's an aquifer.
什么叫蓄水层
What's an aquifer?
就是装水的地方
Well, it's for aqua.
现在都是空的
Well, it's empty now.
好大一只啊
That's a big one.
- 路到头了 - 无路可走了
- It's the end of the line. - Don't go no further.
既然有路 肯定通往什么地方
Now that there is a path. It's got to be connected to something.
你话太多了 能不能放个塞子进去
You talk too much. Why don't you put a cork in it?
你为什么不放个塞子 告诉你哪没有阳光灿烂
Why don't you put a cork... Tell you where the sun don't shine.
你妈妈放了 我会煮了她
Your mama did. I'll cook her right up.
你们两个就是不明白 是吗
You two just don't get it, do you?
有人或者有东西 正在破坏我们的供水
Someone or something is messing with our hydration
那管子肯定和这有关
and that pipe has got something to do with it.
我还以为我们在 追踪银行劫犯
I thought we was following bank robbers!
我们正在经历模式转换
We're experiencing a paradigm shift.
如果你不闭嘴 我会让你面目全非
I'm gonna shift the features on your face if you don't shut up!
来试试
Go ahead and try!
安静 你们这些野蛮人 都给我闭嘴 你们影响我沉思了
Quiet, you savages! Stop your rattling. You're affecting my cogitation.
哇哦 我想到了 把火把灭了
Whoa! I got it. Snuff out them torches.
就是这样
Sure enough.
这想法很犀利啊  伙计
Smart thinking there, feller.
- 开始爬吧 - 别把你脚踩我脸上
- Start climbing. - Get your foot out of my face!
还不赖 是吧  豆豆
Not bad, huh, Beans?
你再这么想 帽子就要着火了
You keep thinking like that, your hat's gonna catch on fire.
哦 你懂的 运气来了你挡也...
Well, you know, you get on a roll, you just...
烫 烫 烫
Hot, hot! Burn.
真可怜 他们只想要一点水
Poor things. All they wanted was a little water.
仙人掌都渴死了 不是好兆头啊
Cactus dying of thirst. It don't bode well.
- 嘿 看我发现什么了 - 找到什么了
- Hey, look what I found! - What you got there?
- 我先看到的 - 嘿 这是我的
- I saw that first! - Hey, that's mine!
你给我
Give me that!
反正是空的
It's empty anyway.
我就知道
I knew that.
你在哪发现的
Where'd you find that?
治安官! 你肯定想看看这个
Sheriff! You're going to want to see this!
是银行的梅里马克先生
It's Mr Merrimack from the bank.
他怎么会在这?
What's he doing here?
- 大家往后站 - 好了 让我看看
- Everybody stand back. - All right, let me see.
看起来像是那些恶棍 朝他后背开了黑枪
Looks like them varmints shot him in the back.
不是 这人不是被枪杀的 他是淹死的
No, this man wasn't shot. He was drowned!
- 淹死的? - 在沙漠里?
- Drowned? - In the middle of the desert?
哦 死者安息吧
What a way to go.
看这些靴子印 是谁的?
Well, now, whose boot prints are those?
有点意思 地面还是潮的
That's interesting. The ground's still wet.
我想我们应该安葬他
I suppose we should bury him.
我不知道 鸟也需要食物
I don't know. Birds got to eat, too.
Circle of life!
食物链!
治安官
Sherriff.
你能说点什么吗
Will you say a few words?
好 好
Yeah. Yeah.
敬爱的人们
Dearly beloved.
今天我们会聚于此
We are gathered here today to honour this man.
缅怀梅里马克先生
Mr Merrimack,
你有权保持沉默
you have the right to remain silent.
要么现在开口 要么永远保持沉默
Speak now or forever hold your peace.
阿门
Amen.
- 阿门 - 阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
嘿 那个该死的印第安人在干什么
Hey! What's that dad-gum Indian doing?
你似乎是在和灵魂协商?
I see you're consulting with the spirits.
不 我在蜕皮 也就是我准备好交配了
No, I'm moulting. Means I'm ready to mate.
呃 这个我记下了
I'll keep that in mind.
仙人掌果
Cactus fruit.
是啊 古老的仙人掌果实
Ah, yes. The ancient cactus fruit.
我知道你们那的人做家乡菜时
I believe your people use it as seasoning
都拿它当调味品
when preparing your native dishes.
也是天然的泻药
Also natural laxative.
有情况
Pick up trail.
有三个人正往西走 其中一个是瞎子 一个
Three men heading west. One blind, one with
有超大前列腺 骑的是女式马鞍
enlarged prostate, riding sidesaddle.
- 他说什么 - 他们骑的是女式马鞍
- What did he say? - They're riding sidesaddle.
- 小点声 - 他说什么
- We're whispering. - What'd he say?
有人阀门不好使了?
Someone's got a bad valve.
好了 你们谁需要检查一下?
All right, which one of you fellers needs a check-up?
太尴尬了
Awkward.
呃 现在到底要做什么啊?
What exactly are we going to do now?
现在 上马出发!
Now we ride!
意思就是我们现在马上出发 就是此刻!
That means we're riding now! This moment.
这些棉花糖让我想起 以前跟老爸一起露营
Marshmallows remind me of going camping with my daddy.
我可以吃上一整晚
I could eat them all night long.
当然了 他会让我再咳出来当早餐
Of course he did make me cough them back up again for breakfast.
有一回 我咳出了一整只斑点狗
This one time, I coughed up an entire Dalmatian.
这算不了什么 我咳出过一整个部落的小矮人
That ain't nothing. I coughed up a whole tribe of pygmies.
他们就在那诡异的看着我
They started looking at me weird.
我还记得他们 他们相当的友好
I remember them. They was quite friendly.
有一回 我在自己粪便里 发现了根人类脊柱
I found a human spinal column in my fecal matter once.
你可能应该去看一下
You might want to get that looked at.
把豆子递给我 豆豆
Pass the beans, Beans.
- 治安官先生? - 不了 谢谢
- Sheriff? - No, thanks.
雷哥先生? 你能不能 给我们讲讲西部之魂?
Mr Rango? Can you tell us about the Spirit of the West?
- 对 讲讲 - 大家传说的是真的么?
- Yeah, tell us about that. - Is it true what they say?
啊 西部之魂!
Yes, the Spirit of the West!
永远高不可攀的理想
The eternally unattainable ideal.
大家说他驾着大理石造就的马车
They say he rides in an alabaster carriage
有金色的守卫保护
with golden guardians to protect him.
而他 只会出现在那些 敢于进行史诗般的探求...
But he only appears to those who have undertaken an epic quest!
并成功到达...
And have made it
另一边的人面前
to the other side.
啥的另一边啊?
The other side of what?
这是个隐喻
It's a metaphor.
嗷 我的眼睛!
My eye!
这个马上就会长好了
That's gonna heal right up.
治安官? 那你打算 怎么对付响尾蛇詹克?
Sheriff? What are you going to do about Rattlesnake Jake?
什么? 哪呢?
What? Where?
对不起哈 有传言说 你已经跟他干过一两次了
Sorry about that. Word is you come against him once or twice.
啊
Yeah.
詹克啊 你是说我兄弟?
Jake. You mean my brother.
- 你兄弟? - 我就是这么说的!
- Your brother? - That's what I said!
可他是条蛇 而你是只蜥蜴啊
But he's a snake and you're a lizard.
呃 我妈社交生活比较活跃
Well, Momma had an active social life.
那他咬过你么?
Did he ever bite you?
当然了 看这个 宝贝 没事 你可以摸下
Sure enough did. Look at that baby. Go ahead, you can touch it.
有意思 这里有个肚脐
That's interesting. That there's a belly button.
很幸运 我对他的毒液免疫
Luckily, I'm immune to his venom.
放在我咖啡里 只能稍微提升点味道
Put some in my coffee just to give it a little tang.
他只害怕鹰 是真的么?
Is it true he's only scared of them hawks?
这就是我们所说的"天敌"
Them's what we call his natural predator.
谈论那条蜿蜒的恶魔 让我羽毛都要乍起来了!
All this talk of that serpentine devil is putting my quills on edge!
我今晚不睡了 绝不 先生
I ain't sleeping tonight. No, sir.
你们大家一点也不用担心 等到明天 咱们就能找到水
Don't you all worry about a thing. Come tomorrow, we'll locate that water
然后英雄般凯旋
and return to a hero's welcome.
朋友们 在咱们睡下之前
Friends, before we bunk down
我想咱们应该牵起手来
I'd like us all to join hands for a moment,
对西部之魂说几句
say a few words to the Spirit of the West.
好主意
That's a good idea.
虽然并不是经常对你说话 西部之魂
Ain't always spoken rightly to you, Spirit of the West.
但今晚 我想感谢你 因为你将雷哥治安官送进我们的生活
But tonight I want to thank you for bringing Sheriff Rango into our lives.
我们生活的很艰难
It's a hard life we got.
有时候我都不知道 还能不能坚持下去
Sometimes I don't know how we're gonna make it.
但不知怎么的 雷哥治安官总能让我相信 我们能行的
But somehow, Sheriff Rango makes me think we will.
我们需要一位勇士 你赐予了我们一位
We needed a brave man and you sent us one.
又有人可以信赖的感觉 真的很好
Nice to have someone to believe in again.
谢谢你 西部之魂 阿门
Thank you, Spirit of the West. Amen.
- 阿门 - 阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
哦 检查一下而已
Just checking.
- 今晚有些凉的 - 谢谢
- It's a little cold tonight. - Thank you.
你有没有感觉到 这些东西在看你?
You ever feel like those things are looking at you?
那是凤尾兰
That's a Spanish dagger.
但在这里 我们都叫它们"会走的仙人掌"
But around here, we just call them the Walking Cactus.
会走?
Walking?
有一则古老的传说 说它们为了找水 会步行穿越沙漠
There's an old legend they actually walk across the desert to find water.
我还小的时候 总会盯着它们看到很晚 看它们是不是真的会动
When I was a little girl, I'd stay up late watching them, to see if they'd move.
我曾经想着 如果我能跟着它们 就能去到某个极好的地方
I thought if I could follow them, they'd lead me to someplace wonderful.
某个不愁水的地方
Someplace with enough water for everyone.
一晚又一晚 我看着它们 从没看到它们移动过
Night after night, I watched them. I never saw them move.
但你仍然在坚持?
But you're still watching.
有谁不想找一个好地方呢?
Who doesn't want to find someplace wonderful?
我们会找到水的 豆豆 我向你保证
We'll find the water, Beans. I promise you.
这叫声真寂寞啊
That's such a lonely sound.
你有寂寞过么?
You ever get lonely?
有时候会吧
Sometimes.
我完全无法想象 你这么有魅力 所有人都喜欢你
I can't imagine it. You're such a charmer and everyone likes you so much.
- 我从没这么容易交到过朋友 - 没有么?
- I never made friends easy like that. - No?
是啊 农场那边 相当的与世隔绝
No, we're pretty isolated out there on the ranch,
就像是被关在一个小盒里
sort of like being sealed up in a little box.
真的见不到太多的人
Don't really see a lot of folks.
我完全不知道 那是什么感觉
I wouldn't know what that's like.
在你的生命中 有什么特殊的人么 雷哥?
There someone special in your life, Rango?
曾经有啦 但她没能保住脑袋
There used to be. But she couldn't keep her head.
而且 我的生活太危险了 不适合这种事情
Besides, my life's too dangerous for that kind of thing.
你也知道 在大草原上 独自生活很糟的
You know, it's an awful solitary existence out there on the prairie.
在山丘间穿行 诸如此类的
Riding the ranges and the suchlike.
豆豆?
Beans?
我要把你活剥了 小子! 我要打的你老妈都认不出!
I'm gonna skin you alive, boy! I'm gonna whup you like a red-headed stepchild!
一帮暴躁的恶棍啊 是吧?
Choleric varmints, ain't they?
病态的家庭 需要矫正
Dysfunctional family. Need intervention.
什么过来了?
What's that coming?
是水
It's the water.
我有个计划 大家每个人 都有各自的分工
I have a plan, and each and every one of you has a part to play.
我做什么?
What do I do?
勺子 你要做的是重中之重
Spoons, you got the most important job of all.
你留在这里 一旦事有不对
You stay up here on the ridge, and if anything goes wrong,
你就给大家发信号
you give the signal.
嘿 豆豆 你穿多大的裙子?
Hey, Beans. What size dress you wearing?
- 他成功了! - 哈利路亚!
- He got it! - Hallelujah!
- 他找到水了! - 你成功了 儿子
- He found the water! - You did it, son.
呃 实际上...
Well, actually...
你怎么就不能 像你兄弟这么有头脑?
Why can't you be all brainy like your brother?
爸爸 关于这水 我有事要告诉你
Pappy, about that water. There's something I gots to tell you.
闭嘴 有人来了
Hush up, now. Somebody's coming.
好先生们 恭敬的祝您 还有您 还有您 下午好
Good sirs, gracious good afternoon to thee and thee and thee.
我为您带来卢蓬夫人
May I present Madame Lupone's
舞蹈马戏团的旅行艺人们
Terpsichorean Troupe of Travelling Thespians!
- 怎么回事? - 我想他们是流浪艺人
- What is that? - I think they's thespians.
流浪艺人? 这在七个州都是违法的
Thespians? That's illegal in seven states!
舞台场景就绪 公主准备了却余生
The stage is set. The princess prepares to take her own life.
我渴望爱情
I yearn for love.
同时 孤独的哨兵守卫着城堡大门
Meanwhile, the lone sentry stands watch at the castle gate.
端立着守卫城堡大门
Stands watch at the castle gate...
听 谁在哪?
Hark! Who goes there?
这情节太老土了
This plot is highly predictable.
安静 这是我最爱的部分
Quiet! This is my favourite part.
随着恢弘的号角声 她年迈的父亲来了
Arriving to great fanfare 'twas her aged father,
被丘比特之箭射中了
strucketh by Cupid.
请您放开我美丽的女儿
Prithee, unhand my fair daughter
向…
and reach for the...
- 啥词? - "举手向天"
- Line? - "Reach for the sky!"
怎么回事?
What was that?
一定是仿真剧
Must be that immersive theatre.
你们被包围了
We got you surrounded!
你和你全家人把手举起来
You and your entire family get your hands up where I can see them.
我全家人?
My entire family?
沙砾 口水 绿领子
Grits and spit and collard greens
松饼 戏剧 猴脑子
Waffle chitlins, monkey brains
泥浆 骨头 粘涕血
Refried bones and booger blood
咸鸭蛋加挡泥板
Pickled eggs and flaps of mud
满坑满谷的人
It's a full house.
看来咱们现在是典型的 老式对峙局面
Looks like we're gonna have ourselves a good old-fashioned standoff.
告诉你们 这里还不是我们所有的人马
I'll have you know, you're not looking at our entire contingent.
这什么 这啥意思?
What's that supposed to be?
那是信号
That's the signal.
是信号 一定出什么事了
That's the signal! Something must have gone wrong!
那么说 呃... 要发生什么事了?
So something's supposed to happen?
呃 我乐意听取你的建议
I am open to suggestions.
跑啊
Run!
上马车
Get on the wagon!
伙计们 我们是不是该活动活动了?
Should we have ourselves some sport, chill'ens?
我喜欢看他们逃命
I likes it when they run.
梅宝 喊吧
Maybelle, give the holler!
看来我们成功了
Looks like we made it!
观众们反响很热烈啊
That audience was quite responsive.
我看他们这一家就快断种了
Yeah, well, I think that chromosome pool is about dried up.
有蝙蝠!
We got bats!
快来 你驾车
Here! You drive.
看来今晚有汤喝了
Looks like there's gonna be soup tonight!
冲啊 抓住他们
Come on, let's get some!
你这个蠢货 不要打到水
What in tarnation? Don't shoot the water!
杰迪代亚 阿拉巴马挤压阵!
Jedidiah! It's time for the Alabama squeeze box!
好的 老爸
Okay, Pa!
我感到了杀气
I am sensing hostility.
攻击来了!
Incoming!
你好哇
Hello!
再见啦
Goodbye!
套住那只猪
Lasso that swine!
我建议我们采用避难方案
I suggest we take evasive action!
我建议你闭嘴 好好开枪
I suggest you shut up and shoot!
- 治安官呢? - 他先行赴约去了
- What happened to the Sheriff? - He had a previous engagement!
布瑟福斯 给他们来点空降
Boseefus, give them some gumbo now!
怎么回事 上去看看
What was that? Go check it out!
怎么了 有麻烦了?
What is it? Is there a problem?
呃 你可以这么说
You could call it that.
小心头痛哦
Headache.
你就这几招吗
Is that all you got?
这也不是很无聊嘛
That wasn't altogether unpleasant!
吃我一枪
Eat lead!
来 拿着这个
Here, hold these.
把你的手拿开
Get your hands off me!
噢 抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
跳
Jump!
这不可能
It's impossible.
不可能 是空的
It can't be. It's empty.
没有水
There's no water!
没有水? 那我们在打什么啊?
No water? Then what the hell we been fighting for?
先生 是你毁坏玷污了 我们赖以生存的资源!
Sir, you have defiled and desecrated the very sustenance of our livelihood!
我想这个穿着脏裙子的家伙 是治安官
I think that there fella in the purty dress is the Sheriff.
就是给我们开勘探许可证的那个?
That's the same fellow what give us a prospecting permit?
- 什么 - 跟这个没关系 没什么
- A what? - Irrelevant! Obfuscation.
你和你家人被捕了 罪名是抢劫银行
You and your kin are under arrest for bank robbery
并杀害了我们敬爱的财务顾问
and the murder of our beloved financial advisor
约翰尼斯・梅里马克 三世 又名毛绒乔
Johannes Merrimack the Third, AKA, Fluffy Joe.
治安官 我们没杀人
Sheriff, we didn't kill nobody.
我们挖地道进了金库 但里面什么都没有
We done tunnelled into that vault, but there weren't nothing in it.
有人在我们之前抢了银行
Somebody done robbed that bank before we robbed it.
那你从哪搞到这水桶的?
Then where'd you get this here jug?
这就是我想告诉你的 爸
That's what I been trying to tell you, Pappy.
我在沙漠里找到的
I found it in the desert.
那见鬼的 你带回来做什么?
Then why in tarnation did you bring it here?
等等 你是说找到这桶时 就是空的?
Hold on! You're saying this here jug was empty when you found it?
对
That's right.
我不相信你的话
I don't believe a word of it.
- 把他们吊死 治安官 - 吊死他们
- Let's hang them, Sheriff! - String them up!
谁会把水倒到沙漠里?
Who'd dump water in the desert?
这也不是第一次了
Wouldn't be the first time.
这是个谜题! 就像张古老的X光片!
It's a puzzle! It's like a big old mammogram!
到底怎么回事 治安官?
What's going on, Sheriff?
我不知道
I don't know.
不过我会揭开这秘密 暴露里面的阴谋
But I'm going to strip away this mystery and expose its private parts.
你和你儿子跟我走
You and your kin are coming with me.
他们回来了
They're coming!
Here they come!
似乎他们抓到劫匪了
Looks like they got them robbers.
水在哪呢?
Where's the water?
没有水
There weren't no water.
他去哪啊?
Where is he going?
去见镇长
He's going to see the Mayor.
啊 他会很高兴的
He's got to be pleased with that.
好球 老板
That's a good one, boss!
真是有趣
That's interesting.
关于鞋的事 我很抱歉 雷哥先生
I do apologise for the shoes, Mr Rango,
不过这游戏有自己的规则 你应该明白的
but there's a certain protocol to this game, you understand.
我是个循规蹈矩的人
I'm a bit of a stickler for protocol.
那很好 因为你要回答几个问题
Well, that's good, 'cause you got a few questions to answer
而我 也有自己的原则
and I've got my own protocol.
但谁会把水倒在沙漠里?
But why would anyone dump water in the blooming desert?
相信银行劫匪的话 这有点幼稚吧
It does seem a bit na'ive, taking the word of admitted bank robbers.
另外 等他们被吊死 你的任务就完成了
Besides, once they hang, your job is done.
- 精彩 - 干得好
- Bravo! - Job well done.
但如果真有人在他们之前 就抢了银行呢
But what if somebody did rob the bank before they got there?
谁会那么做呢 雷哥先生?
And who would do that, Mr Rango?
我还希望你能告诉我呢
I was hoping you could tell me.
这听上去几乎是个指控?
That sounds marginally near to an accusation.
你怎么想都可以
Take it any way you like.
你说过的某些话 一直在我的前额叶翻涌不止
Something you said keeps rattling around in my frontal lobe.
是什么
What's that?
"有水在手 万事不愁"
"Control the water and you control everything."
拜托 雷哥先生
Come now, Mr Rango.
你也把我想得太厉害了
You attribute divine power to me.
我怎么可能控制水呢
How on earth could I possibly control the water?
你显然很精通这个游戏
You've obviously mastered this game.
嗯 我已经玩了很多年了 先生
Well, I've been playing it for many years, sir.
在高速公路切开这大峡谷之前 我就在这里了
I was here before the highway split this great valley.
我亲眼见证了整个事情的发展
I watched the march of progress,
也从中学到了一两件
and I learned a thing or two.
也许你也应该试试看长远些
Perhaps it's time you started to take the long view,
欣赏历史壮阔的潮流
begin to appreciate the broad sweep of history.
看看那边 孩子
Look out there, son.
你能看到时光的流逝
You can almost see time passing.
你在那里修什么
What are you building out here?
未来 雷哥先生 未来
The future, Mr Rango, the future.
很快 这所有的一切 都将成为过去
One day soon, all this is going to fade into myth,
边陲小镇 执法者 神枪手
the frontier town, the lawman, the gunslinger.
再没有他们的容身之处了
There's just no place for them any more.
- 我们现在是文明人了 - 说得对 文明了
- We're civilised now. - That's right, civilised.
那才是未来的方向
That's what the future holds.
你可以成为未来的一部分 也可以被抛在后面
You can either be part of it, or you can be left behind.
梅里马克先生就是这样? 他被抛到后面了?
Is that what happened to Mr Merrimack? Did he get left behind?
小心点 雷哥先生 你似乎忘了自己只是只小蜥蜴
Careful, Mr Rango. You seem to forget you're just one little lizard.
你似乎忘了 在这些事上 我代表着法律
You seem to forget I'm the law around these parts.
我们的新治安官 英雄扮的太久了
Our new sheriff has been playing the hero for so long,
他真开始相信自己就是了
he's actually starting to believe it.
叫响尾蛇詹克来
Call in Rattlesnake Jake.
可詹克是死亡使者
But Jake's the Grim Reaper.
不牺牲人命他是不会走的
He never leaves without taking a blooming soul.
快去
Do it!
别动 见造物主时 看起来要体面一点
Now be still. You gotta look presentable to meet your maker.
* 死亡即将来临 *
Death has arrived
* 英雄如何逃脱 *
How will the hero survive?
镇长买下了峡谷所有的地
The Mayor has bought up all the land in the valley,
除了你的农场 豆豆小姐
except for your ranch, Miss Beans.
这完全说不通 没有水 那片地毫无用处
That just don't make no sense. Without water, that land is useless.
除非他控制了水
Unless he controls the water.
就像猴子的膀胱
Like a monkey's bladder!
然后 一旦他把地都买到 就会把水引回来
Then he could bring it back once he's bought up all the land.
可他怎么控制水呢
But how does he control the water?
呃 得花点时间训练它们
Well, you gotta spend some time and train them.
你也知道 猴子嘛 要是它们尿了 就收拾它们
'Cause you know monkeys, when they do go, you rub their nose in it.
治安官 有麻烦了
Sheriff, we got a problem.
等等 豆豆 不需要用这个
Hold on, Beans. That won't be necessary.
- 吊死他 直到他脸发黑 - 把强盗交出来!
- Hang him till his head turns blue! - Give us them robbers!
等等 大家冷静点 听我说
Hold on! Calm down, everyone! Let me talk!
- 把他们钉死在法院门口 - 冷静下来 大家
- Nail them to the courthouse! - Now, calm down, everybody.
把他们交出来 我们要把他们碎尸万段
Get them out here so we can cut off their giblets!
你也这样 勺子?
You, too, Spoons?
他们抢走了水 抢走了我们的一切
They done taken that water. They taken everything we got!
只要我还是治安官 就不许吊死任何人
No one's stringing anyone up. Not while I'm sheriff.
但这都是他的错
But this is all his fault!
你说了会把水带回来
You said you's gonna bring the water back.
只是... 没有水就没有希望了
It's just, we got no hope without that water.
我们没有什么能相信的了
We got nothing left to believe in.
你们看到那个牌子没有?
You see that sign up there?
只要那个"治安官"的牌子还在
As long as that sign says "Sheriff,"
你们就可以相信 这里还有法律和秩序
you can believe that there's law and order in this town.
可一旦失去了法律和秩序 想想看吧 嗯
But without law and order, ruminate on that. Oh, yeah.
刚开始很慢 就像真菌滋生
Starts out slow, like a fungus.
有人开始抱怨 开始互相指责
Somebody says a cross word. Accusations start flying.
邻居告发邻居 很快 我们会吃掉自己的骨肉
Neighbour turns on neighbour. Pretty soon, we're eating our children!
然后猫猫狗狗搅和在一起
And then dogs and cats are getting together
制造出各种畸形的变异!
to create all sorts of unnatural mutant aberrations!
所以 你想要信赖什么 勺子?
So, you want something to believe in, Spoons?
相信我吧
Believe in me.
相信那个牌子
Believe in that there sign.
只要它还挂在那 我们就有希望
For as long as it hangs there, we got hope.
你好啊 兄弟
Hello, brother.
渴了吗?
Thirsty?
好久不见啊 兄弟 你过得怎么样
Long time, brother. How you been keeping?
噢 你知道...
Well, you know...
我听闻你夸耀说如何只用一发子弹 就把詹金斯七兄弟都干掉了 对吗?
I hear you been telling about how you killed all them Jenkins brothers.With one bullet, wasn't it?
是真的吗
Isn't that right?
这些善良的乡亲们都信以为真了 是吧?
All these good folks here believe your little stories, don't they?
怎么 他们相信你 是个冷血杀手 是吧?
Why, they believe you're just a stone killer, don't they?
看来他们还挺信任你的
Seems these folks trust you.
他们以为你能保护这个小镇
They think you're gonna save their little town.
他们以为你能保护他们弱小的生命
They think you're gonna save their little souls!
可我们更了解你 不是吗?
But we know better, don't we?
何不让你的朋友们 看看你到底是什么?
So why don't you show your friends here what you're made of?
让他们看看你的真面目?
Show them who you really are.
你怎么不干脆一枪打死我?
Why don't you just pull your gun and shoot me?
不过当然 你是不需要这么多的
But, of course, you won't need all these.
一颗就够了 是吧
Just one, right?
来吧 大英雄 开枪吧
Go ahead, hero. Pull the trigger.
孩子 你眼里充满了杀气吗 啊?
You got killer in your eyes, son?
我没看到啊
I don't see it.
你所说的那些事 其实一件也没做过 是吧
You didn't do any of them things you said, did you?
你没杀死过詹金斯兄弟 你甚至不是从西部来的
You didn't kill them Jenkins brothers. You ain't even from the West!
是吧?
Are you?
- 说啊! - 不是
- Say it! - No.
大声点 我想你的朋友们 听不太清吧
Speak up. I don't think your friends here heard you.
不是
No.
你所做的就是 欺骗这些善良的人们
All you've done is lie to these good people.
你就是个骗子 混蛋 没说错吧
You ain't nothing but a fake and a coward. Isn't that right?
是的
Yes.
- 大声点! - 是的
- Louder! - Yes.
听好了 你这个骗子
Listen close, you pathetic fraud.
这个镇现在是我的了
This is my town now.
如果再让我看见你 就将你打入十八层地狱!
If I ever see you again, I will take your soul straight down to hell!
你到底是谁啊?
Who are you?
我是谁?
Who am I?
我谁也不是
I'm nobody.
金色的守卫
Golden guardians.
大理石铸就的车
The alabaster carriage.
西部之魂
The Spirit of the West.
你好啊? 西部之魂先生?
Excuse me? Mister Spirit, sir?
啊 真是漂亮 有时候得 挖的足够深 才能找到要找的
There's a beaut. Sometimes you got to dig deep to find what you're looking for.
所以你做到了
So you made it.
这里是天堂吗
Is this heaven?
如果是的话 我们就该 和金・诺瓦克一起吃小煎饼了
If it were, we'd be eating Pop-Tarts with Kim Novak.
啊
Yeah.
说的是啊 你在这做什么?
No kidding. What are you doing out here?
找寻 和你一样
Searching, same as you.
我都不知道自己要寻找的是什么
I don't even know what I'm looking for any more.
我甚至不知道自己谁
I don't even know who I am.
他们以前都叫你无名氏呢
They used to call you the Man with No Name.
他们现在给所有东西都取了名
These days they got a name for just about everything.
他们怎么叫你并不重要 重要的是你自己要怎么做
Doesn't matter what they call you. It's the deeds make the man.
可我却让事情变得更糟 我是个骗子
Yeah, but my deeds just made things worse. I'm a fraud. I'm a phoney!
我的朋友们信任我 可他们需要的是一个英雄
My friends believed in me, but they need some kind of hero.
那就成为一个英雄
Then be a hero.
不 你不懂 其实我 根本不该在这出现
No. No, no, you don't understand. I'm not even supposed to be here.
没错 你千里迢迢来这 找寻一些根本不存在的东西
That's right. You came a long way to find something that isn't out here.
你还不明白吗? 这不是你的问题
Don't you see? It's not about you.
是他们
It's about them.
可我不能回去了
But I can't go back.
你似乎别无选择 孩子
Don't know that you got a choice, son.
没人能逃出自己的故事
No man can walk out on his own story.
这么说你做到了
So you made it.
没错 朋友 路的另一边
That's right, amigo. The other side of the road.
你都看到了吗?
Did you just see that?
我们只能看到 自己需要看到的
We each see what we need to see.
很美 不是吗
Beautiful, isn't it?
是啊
Yeah.
很美
It is.
来 我给你看点东西
Come, my friend. I want to show you something.
很多年前 整个山谷都被水覆盖
Many years ago, this entire valley was covered in agua.
现在 只有一个疑问
Now only one question remains.
水都到哪去了
Where did it go?
他们顺着水源走
They follow the water.
他们顺着水源走! 来啊!
They follow the water! Come on!
那根本讲不通 没有水 这地一文不值
That just don't make no sense. Without water, that land is useless.
你在这建造什么?
What are you building out here?
未来 雷哥先生
The future, Mr Rango.
你可以成为未来的一部分 也可以被抛在后面
You can either be part of it, or you can be left behind.
在高速公路切开这大峡谷之前 我就在这里了
I was here before the highway split this great valley.
我亲眼见证了整个事情的发展
I watched the march of progress
也从中学到了一两件
and I learned a thing or two.
控制水源
Control the water
就控制了一切
and you control everything.
来吧 雷哥先生
Come now, Mr Rango.
你也把我想得太厉害了
You attribute divine power to me.
我怎么可能控制水呢
How on earth could I possibly control the water?
现在怎样 伙计?
What now, amigo?
没人能逃出自己的故事
No man can walk out on his own story.
我要回去
I'm going back.
为什么
But why?
因为那才是我
Because that's who I am.
敢来这里胆子真不小 你想干什么
You got a lot of nerve showing up here, lawman. What is it you want?
你们老大和他的孩子就要行刑了 可他们是冤枉的
Your pappy and them boys are about to hang for something they didn't do.
不过 我有个主意
But I've got a plan.
我知道对你来说 这有多不容易 豆豆
I appreciate how difficult this is for you, Beans.
可你要做的是正确的决定
But you're making a practical decision.
决定 决定
Decisions, decisions.
不必再遭受那么多痛苦
There's no need for any more suffering.
你们家的农场 现在就是一块荒地
Your family's ranch is nothing but a wasteland now.
把契约签了就可以从 你爸爸留下的负担中解脱
Sign the deed and relieve yourself of your father's burden.
我爸爸不是负担
My daddy was not a burden!
拿回你的臭钱 我的地不卖!
Keep your blood money and I'll keep my land!
照他说的做 不然的话
Do what he says or, by all the fires of the black pit,
我会把你漂亮的眼珠子 从你脑袋上挤出来
I'll squeeze them pretty brown eyes out of your skull!
别急 詹克 不需要
Now, hold on, Jake. There's no need to...
别管我怎么做! 是你让我来的
Let me do my job! You brought me in.
现在我们要把这件事做个了结
Now we're gonna play this thing out to the end!
把那该死的文件签了 女人
Sign the damn paper, woman!
去死吧
Go to hell!
我就是从那儿来的
Where do you think I come from?
看着我的眼睛
Look into my eyes.
我要看着你死
I want to see you die.
詹克!
Jake!
我在叫你呢
I'm calling you out!
詹克!
Jake!
现在越来越有意思了
This day just got a little more interesting.
把她放下
Put her down.
否则呢 小矮子? 你要杀了我吗
Or what, little man? You going to kill me?
那还不是小事一桩
That's just about the size of it.
- 把你的脏手拿开 - 闭嘴
- Get your filthy paws off me! - Shut your gob!
好了 治安官 动手吧
All right, Sheriff, make your move.
动手 伙计们
Now, amigos!
- Heave! Heave! - Heave! Heave!
这主意不怎么样
That was a bad idea.
口渴吗 兄弟?
Thirsty, brother?
水来了
Here it comes!
不 不
No. No!
这真是奇迹
It's a miracle!
小心
Look out!
- 看那边 - 怎么回事?
- Lookee there! - What is that?
是咱的救兵 老爸
It's our salvation, Pa!
监狱炸开了 孩子们 我们可以逃出去了
It's a jailbreak, boys! We're busting out!
我要把你打得满身窟窿 肠子满地流
I'm gonna blow so many holes in you, your guts'll be leaking lead!
幸好我有带帮手
Well, then it's a good thing I brought some backup.
什么
What?
不是鹰
Ain't no hawk.
什么都不是 只是蝙蝠
Ain't nothing but bats!
按计划执行 孩子们 让恶魔的血流干!
Stick to the plan, boys! Let's bleed that devil dry!
一颗子弹足矣
It only takes one bullet.
你还没那胆量
You ain't got the nerve.
试试看啊
Try me.
哦 雷哥先生
Oh, Mr Rango.
你是不是忘了什么事啊？
Aren't you forgetting something?
把枪给我 治安官
Hand me your gun, Sheriff.
现在 雷哥先生
Now, Mr Rango.
豆豆 坚持住 别担心 我有办法
Beans! Hold on. Don't worry, I got a plan.
救命啊!
Help!
把门打开!
Open the door!
好吧 B计划
Okay, plan B.
豆豆 你在说什么呢?
Beans, you're mumbling.
我所有问题都解决了只剩下一个
All my problems taken care of except for one.
现在是新时代了 詹克
It's a new West, Jake.
不能再容忍有枪客的存在 我们现在是生意人了
There's no room for gunslingers any more. We're businessmen now.
我们有新帽子了
Yeah, we got new hats.
我们那儿 管这叫即兴创作
Where I come from, we call this improvisation.
你回来了
You came back.
那是什么啊?
What was that?
不必惊慌 不过我想 你刚把B计划吞掉了
No need to panic, but I think you just swallowed plan B.
什么?
What?
好吧 惊慌的时候到了
Okay, panic time.
你和治安官有太多的相似之处
You and the Sheriff are more alike than you think.
你只不过是个传说而已
You're nothing but legends.
很快就会被人们遗忘的
Pretty soon, no one will believe you even existed.
最后一颗子弹 结束掉最后一个恶棍
One last bullet to kill one last outlaw.
真是完美
How fitting.
治安官 我保证 如果我们能够合作
Sheriff, I'm sure if we work together,
对咱们双方都有利
we can reach a mutually beneficial solution to our current situation.
你最好还是跟他说吧
You better take it up with him.
一颗子弹
One bullet.
向你致敬
I tip my hat to you,
我们都是传奇
one legend to another.
你刚才怎么说来着?
What was that you said?
很快 你就会被人们遗忘的
"Pretty soon, no one will believe you even existed."
不 詹克 不要
No, Jake! No!
雷哥!
Rango!
你兑现了你的诺言 把水找回来了
You brought the water back, just like you promised.
你是真正的英雄
You really are a hero.
嗯 英雄嘛 就是无论何时你...
Well, the thing about heroes is, whenever you...
别把气氛破坏了
Don't spoil it.
好吧
Right.
嗯 你们要干嘛我不清楚 不过我可是 一定要去泡个澡
Well, I don't know about you all, but I could sure go for a dip.
就这样 蜥蜴完成了它的旅程
And so the lizard completes his journey
从默默无闻到今天被传颂的传奇
from humble beginnings to the legend we sing of today.
虽然他肯定免不了一死 可能是死于家庭意外
And although he is certain to die, perhaps from a household accident,
概率占非自然死亡人数的65%
which account for 65o/o of all unnatural deaths,
镇民们会纪念他的
the people of the village will honour his memory
就算是不顾自己的尊严
even as they abandon their dignity.
欢迎来到 沼泽镇
- 我要进去了 - 来杯冷的怎样?
- I'm going in. - How about a cold one, there?
钱是钱 水是水
Water ain't money. Money is money.
嗯 我没有...
Well, I ain't got no...
有麻烦了
We have a problem.
是谁让他进池子的?
Who let Snuggles in the pool again?
真的 我觉得你让我完整了
I really think you complete me.
求你 放开我的少女
Prithee, unhand my fair maiden.
- 卡 来第五次 - 他们怎么能忍受这个?
- Cut. Cut. Everybody, take five. - How can they take this any more?
啊 你们这些小毛孩
Oh, you kids.
你干嘛啊?
What did you do that for?
我只是想检查下 希望你没有晒伤
I was just checking. I hope you don't get too sunburned.
那样可以把一个人的脸都撕下来
You can peel a man's face right off.
- 这是什么东西? - 人类的脾脏
- What is it? - That there's some human spleen.
别碰
Don't touch it.
这已经是第二次发生了
That's the second time that's happened to me.
这水上活动真不错
This water thing's great.
我正在小便
I'm urinating right now.
接下来五分钟 成人时间
Adult swim, next five minutes.
不要游到浮标以外
Stay between the buoys.
你的午餐装好了 有丹麦面包
I packed your lunch. Danish is in there
知道你不喜欢 我把葡萄干都挑出来了
and I picked the raisins out just the way you like it.
别忘了 喷鼻子的药 放在鞍袋里
Don't forget, your nasal spray is in your saddle-bag...
- 豆豆! - 你的润肤露
- Beans! ...and your moisturising lotion...
- 豆豆 我们说过这事的 - 润肤露?
- Now, Beans! We've talked about this. - Lotion?
是擦枪用的 是枪支润滑剂
That's for my gun. That's gun lotion.
治安官 你要去哪?
Sherriff, where are you headed?
下游那边出了点麻烦 坏比尔又出来活动了
There's trouble down a dry creek. Bad Bill's been acting up again.
亲爱的 你得保证毫发无损的回来
Now, honey, you come back with all your digits.
不要再逞强做什么英雄了
And don't go trying to be a hero.
豆豆 你不明白
Beans, you are missing the point.
我得维护我的形象
I got an image to protect now.
我的糖哪去了?
Where's my Tic Tacs?
- 我找到了 - 怎么回事?
- I found them. - What's going on?
哦 为了满足公众的美好愿望
You know, in order to satisfy the needs of the collective,
英雄必须抛去自我
the hero must abandon the self
将自己塑造成 让人永远崇拜的偶像
and solidify his image as an icon that will forever be remembered.
所以 这算是英雄迟暮
So, this is the sunset shot.
为他们鼓掌吧 伙计
Give them a good one, amigo.
准备好了吗?
Ready, Excelsior?
我的战友
My fellow comrades.
人的一生总会遇到犹豫不决
There will be times when you doubt yourself.
或遭受沉痛打击
When you feel pummelled by the cataclysms of life,
紧记 此时此刻 还有我
remember this moment. Remember me.
我会一直看着你
Know that I will be there watching you,
偶尔时机也许会不太恰当
sometimes at inappropriate moments.
但就这么说定了
That's part of the deal.
同时 不要忘记 在我们内心深处
And remember, within all of us resides
有着真正的... 喔
the true Spirit of the...
Let's take it from the top.
咱们从头再来一次吧